# Joseph Knox

650.709.7272 | joseph.edward.knox@gmail.com | Github: jknox13 | LinkedIn: Joseph Knox

## **EDUCATION**

## **UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON**

M.S. IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS June 2018 | Seattle, WA

#### UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

B.S. IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING Minor in Applied Mathematics June 2016 | Seattle, WA

## **SKILLS**

## **TECHNICAL**

Languages: Python • C • PhP/Hack • R

ML libs: SkLearn • XGBoost • PyTorch

DB (SQL): Presto • Hive • MySQL • Spark

Linux (Arch, Debian) • Docker

## **OPEN SOURCE**

## MCMODELS | MAINTAINER

2017 - 2018 | Python

Python library for mesoscopic full-brain connectivity models in mouse – built on top of the AllenSDK and Scikit-Learn APIs.

## **RISTRETTO** | PRIMARY CONTRIBUTOR 2018 | Python

Randomized matrix factorization library written in Python (numpy).

#### CONTRIBUTER TO

- Allensdk
- Scikit-learn

## COURSEWORK

## **GRADUATE**

Statistical Computing Combinatorial Optimization Computational Neuroscience Statistical Analysis of Social Networks Computational Methods - Data Analysis

#### **UNDERGRADUATE**

Machine Learning Stochastic Modeling/Decision Analysis Linear and Network Programming High-Performance Scientific Computing

## SUMMARY

I am a Data Scientist with 3+ years of experience driving business impact through research, analytics, and engineering. Throughout my diverse work experience, I have identified, communicated, and solved various levels of problems with close collaboration with cross-functional partners.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FACEBOOK**

DATA SCIENTIST

Sept 2018 - Present · 1 yr 11 mos

San Francisco, CA

- Own analytic strategy focused on Instagram SMB advertiser value
- Identify product gaps and market opportunities, working with many cross-functional partners to influence product and marketing roadmaps
- Build end-to-end ML models to predict advertiser churn and retention lift
- Build and contribute to internal tools streamlining data visualization, ML modeling, and experimentation measurement
- Write data pipelines to support analysis, internal tools, and external personalized marketing campaigns

#### ALLEN INSTITUTE FOR BRAIN SCIENCE

**DATA ANALYST** 

June 2017 - Sept 2018 · 1 yr 4 mos

Seattle, WA

- Develop and implement novel models for full-brain connectivity
- Analyze heterogeneous, multi-scale experimental data
- Contribute to organizational open source software packages
- Research statistical, graph theoretic models of brain connectivity

## **RATLAB LLC**

RESEARCH INTERN

July 2016 - Jan 2017 · 7 mos

Seattle, WA

- Designed and conducted experiments for product R&D
- Optimized hardware design through the use of statistical ML techniques

#### **COLLEGE WORKS PAINTING**

Manager

Feb 2015 - Sept 2015 · 8 mos

Seattle, WA

- Acted as project manager sourcing clients and creating estimates for management of monetary funds
- Planned production schedule and successfully coordinated all projects, interacting with clients daily and ensured customer satisfaction
- Recruited, hired, and trained 3 employees

## SELECT PUBLICATIONS

- [1] J. A. Harris, S. Mihalas, et al. Hierarchical organization of cortical and thalamic connectivity. *Nature*, 575(7781):195–202, 2019.
- [2] J. E. Knox, K. D. Harris, et al. High-resolution data-driven model of the mouse connectome. *Network Neuroscience*, 3(1):217–236, 2019.
- [3] J. D. Whitesell et al. Whole brain imaging reveals distinct spatial patterns of amyloid beta deposition in three mouse models of alzheimer's disease. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 527(13):2122–2145, 2019.